# Brianna Hinds

(210)-288-7673 | briden32016@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/brianna-hinds | github.com/briannaghinds | briannaghinds.dev

## Summary

Highly motivated computer science student with 4 years of programming experience and a passion for artificial intelligence, machine learning, and data analytics. Eager to apply academic knowledge, problem solving skills, and practical experience to contribute to innovative projects and grow as a programmer. Also, a dedicated D1 track and field athlete, demonstrating adaptiveness, discipline, determination, and teamwork.

## EDUCATION

## **Houston Christian University**

Houston, TX

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Data Analytics

August 2022 - Present

- Extracurricular: Part of the HCU Track Team, President of Robotics and Engineering Organization
- Relevant Coursework: Data Analytics, Operating Systems, Data Structures, Database Management Systems

## PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

## Data Science Researcher

August 2024 – Present

Purdue University

West Lafayette, IN, Remote

- Collaborating with Houston Fire Department on analyzing their station data to improve HFD performance.
- Developing data-driven strategies to optimize resource allocation and response times.
- Applying Python and R, I am implementing data science cleaning, processing, and visualization tools to present the results of the analysis.

# Machine Learning Research Assistant

May 2024 - Present

Houston Christian University

Houston, TX

- Applying my knowledge in PyTorch and data analysis, I built a Graph Convolution Networks (GCN) to aid in the prediction of cancers types based on gene expressions. Visualizations such as tSNE were implemented to show the relationship of the data.
- Fine tuned a GCN using Bayesian Optimization to find a classification model architecture of 96% accuracy.
- Applying Python and R, I am implementing data cleaning, processing, and visualization tools to present the results
  of the analysis.

## Computing Teaching Assistant

August 2023 – Present

Houston Christian University

Houston, TX

- Assisting professors in executing ABET-accredited curriculum.
- Aiding students in understanding computer science concepts, project planning, and/or college guidance.
- Getting hands-on experience in teaching a classroom of students computer science courses/topics.

# Projects

## NASAMINDS: AI Inventory Tracking | Python, PyTorch, Matplotlib

January 2024 – March 2024

- Built, trained, and tested an Artificial Neural Network to localize an object on an x-y plane based on RFID data (signals and frequency).
- Model concluded with very low error and our mapping visualization showed the ANN model's accuracy for predicting where an item was.

**Sky-5O** | Python, Open Computer Vision, Tello Drone

March 2023 – May 2023

- Developed a license plate detection system that implemented a GUI to control the drone with a connected computer keyboard.
- User can operate takeoff, landing, and the drone's camera; where it can take a picture and record the license plate in a text file.
- Received an "Innovation Award" for demonstrating exceptional creativity and originality in its concepts and design.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, R, Java, Arduino/C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C

Frameworks/Technologies: Object-Oriented Programming, Machine Learning Models, Neural Networks, PyTorch Skills: Time Management, Communication, Teamwork, Leadership, Microsoft Excel, Data Cleansing, Git, GitHub